

## CONTACT

- itmacaranas.qualityworks@gmail.com
- +63956-253-1708
- Calmar Subdivision, Lucena City, Quezon Province, Philippines

### **EXPERTISE**

- Microsoft Word
- Microsoft Excel
- Microsoft Powerpoint
- Bookkeeping
- Auditing
- Tax Filing
- Graphic Designing
- Video Editing

# ISAAC DOMINIC T. MACARANAS

#### Certified Public Accountant

A Certified Public Accountant with 7 years of accounting related experience. Holder of a Bachelor of Science in Accountancy Degree in Polytechnic University of the Philippines. Seeks to leverage accounting expertise to contribute growth and development in a company.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **AUDITOR**

July 2017 - May 2019

**KPMG** Philippines

- Performed full scope audit which includes audit planning, business process understanding, fluctuation analytics, internal controls identification and evaluation, significant accounts identification and evaluation and preparation and review of year-end financial reports for statutory requirements.
- Handled an audit client which is publicly-listed in the Philippines.
- Assisted in the carrying of quality audit and other assurance services to clients in multiple industries.
- Performed day-to-day activities of audit engagements of various clients such as business process reviews, controls testing and substantive procedures.
- Communicated audit issues and findings directly to supervisor and ,where applicable, to manager and partner for resolution.
- Assisted and coach new audit staff in the engagement in preparing clear and accurate work papers.

#### MANAGING PARTNER June 2019 - Present

Duldulao Macaranas and Associates Co.

 Manages overall accounting, tax, audit related matters and provides practical solutions to clients for mandatory compliance with government authorities.

# **EDUCATION**

Polytechnic University of the Philippines 2012 - 2016

• Bachelor of Science in Accountancy